Samuel Marks

206.601.9523 | <u>samuelmarks81@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/samuel-j-marks

UX DESIGNER: Helping people be more effective

Over 3 years professional UX Designer experience, helping push the release of many products and gaining extensive knowledge of best practices for user experience design and information architecture. Regularly collaborate with multiple teams and stakeholders, clearly and effectively communicating complex design concepts. Work directly with developers and engineers to translate customer needs and design insight into technical requirements.

- MANAGEMENT STYLE: Agile. Waterfall.
- WEB TRENDS: User-Centered. Responsive.
- COMMUNICATION: Active Listener. Public Speaking. Collaborative.
- PROBLEM-SOLVING: Critical Thinker. Asks Questions. Validates Assumptions. Detail Oriented.

COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

SKILLS

SOFTWARE

User Research Video Production Persona Development Prototyping Data Visualization User Journey Mapping **Usability Testing** Interaction Design User Experience Design Technical Writing Mobile App Design Visual Design HTML/CSS/JavaScript

- XD InVision
- Axure Tableau Zeplin Power BI Sketch InDesign

- Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop

Microsoft Office: Excel, Word, Outlook, PowerPoint, SharePoint, Teams.

ONLINE PORTFOLIO: http://www.samuelmarksdesign.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGNER 2018-present

Amazon via Fiduciary Tech. Bellevue, WA

Conduct user research and usability testing, and create wireframes, hi-fidelity mockups, and interactive prototypes for the redesign of an internal web-application used by 10,000+ users across 10 countries. Information architecture and interaction design, data analysis, and presentations.

- Conducted over 30 hours of usability testing with target audience
- Improved discoverability and success rate for critical features by 100%
- Identified and solved for gaps between current design and the mental model of target au-
- Identified and solved for logic errors that restricted users from viewing critical data
- Improved discoverability of general program information by 40%

UX DESIGNER CONTRACTOR

2015-present

Samuel Marks Design. Lake Stevens, WA

Provide user research, user experience design, usability testing and data analysis to clients through private contracts. Common deliverables include field studies, competitive analyses, heuristic evaluations, user personas, journey maps, information architecture, wireframes, mockups, interactive prototypes, design specifications, usability tests, data analyses, and reports.

- Created data visualization tool that allowed sales team to compare multivariate data and identify new sales opportunities and use time more effectively
- Delivered product below budget and 3 weeks ahead of deadline
- Increased client's sales volume by 20%

UX DESIGNER II

2016-2017

Whiting House Group. Lenexa, KS. Remote.

Conducted user research and usability testing. Analyzed research results and presented findings. Created sketches, wireframes, mockups and interactive prototypes. Created assets in Sketch and Axure libraries. Communicated exceptional experiences to both stakeholders and users.

- Standardized many aspects of in-house user experience practice, especially in the area of interaction design, resulting in decreased redundancy and improved efficiency of team's workflow
- Pushed the release of large scale intranet application for major pharmacy benefits manager
- Conducted 100+ hours of user research and usability testing
- Reduced patient infusion fulfillment times by 64%
- 400% increase in productivity
- Increased revenue by 4x

UX/UI CONSULTANT

2016-2016

Design JMB; Redmond, WA

Collaborated with stakeholders and clients to elicit design requirements. Designed and prototyped UI/UX design solutions using Axure, Sketch, and Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator and communicated, negotiated, and justified intelligent design decisions to stakeholders and clients.

Delivered design insights and informed solutions on par with a highly experienced UX design team. Offered full-time position with actively consulting client as a result of exceptional performance

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Bachelor of Science: Human Centered Design & Engineering: Human-Computer Interaction University of Washington. Seattle, WA. 2016